RAGHWENDRA SINGH

ANDROID DEVELOPER



+46-730376661

raghav.2945@gmail.com

- Solvändan 11 D, Lund
- in in/raghwendrasingha/

SKILLS

- Android Framework Customization
- Android NDK/SDK
- HAL, HIDL, JNI, DI (Hilt), RxJava
- Language C++, Java, Kotlin
- Unit testing Junit, Mocikto
- Tools JIRA, Buganizer, Android
 Studio, IntelliJ, Unity, GitHub, Linux
- Problem Solving
- Agile, Scrum
- Strong Communication

EDUCATION

MASTER OF SCIENCE

Information System

Linneaus University

2020 - 2023

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY

Computer Science

Lovely Professional University 2008 - 2012

PROFILE

I am a qualified and experienced full-stack Android developer with a decade of experience in customizing Android frameworks, integrating and porting operating systems, and delivering highly scalable, optimized, and efficient Android applications across multiple platforms. These platforms include TV, Mobile, Tablet, Watches, and Android Automotive. My proficiency spans Java, Kotlin, C++, Android SDK, and the Linux environment. I possess excellent creative and analytical abilities and am known for being a team player with a keen attention to detail.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR ANDROID CONSULTANT Sony Nordic

April 2023 - Present

- Conducted debugging of Java and C++ code to identify and resolve technical challenges promptly.
- Collaborated with platform vendors and Google on bug fixes and enhancements, ensuring product quality and performance.
- Contributed code to AOSP for SystemUI enhancements.
- Orchestrated overlay management, consolidating variables for diverse models.

PARTNER ANDROID DEVELOPER Google

Sep 2020 - March 2023

- Application development using Single Activity architecture,
 AndroidX navigation, Jetpack Compose, adhering to Google best practices with MVVM, Hilt, and Gradle.
- Good working experience with live-data, dependency injection and reactive patterns.
- Incorporate, adjust, and enhance new OS versions designed for wearables
- AOSP changes under CTS and Wear OS-specific test suits.

LANGUAGE

ENGLISH

Bilingual proficiency

HINDI

Native

OTHER EXP.

- Game development experience.
- ML/Al Theoritical knowledge.
- Product Management Theoritical knowledge.

FREELANCE EXPERIENCE

ANDROID ENGINEER Audiomack

- Led expansion of music streaming app to diverse platforms: Android TV,
 Android Automotive, and Android wearables.
- Collaborated to raise ANR-free sessions from 93% to >97% and crashfree sessions from 98.9% to >99.7% through systematic enhancements.
- Utilized specialized mobile tools (Embrace, Bitrise) for efficient development and monitoring.

SENIOR ANDROID CONSULTANT Sigma Connectivity

Oct 2019 - March 2023

- Device specific native application development.
- Worked in input source handling (Linux Input System)- Touch & Pen.
- Exposure to HID (Human Interface Devices) interfaces.
- Worked with C++ 11, HIDL and Protobuffer.
- Board bring up Qualcomm
- Worked on Device tree, device descritor and input methods.

SENIOR ANDROID DEVELOPER

Harman India

May 2018 - Sep 2019

- Integeration of android-auto receiver library with Android head unit OS.
- · Wired and wireless projection support
- Experience in BT profile HFP & A2DP
- Exposure to Android boot optimization, VHAL and Android audio system

SENIOR ANDROID DEVELOPER

Altisource Business Solution Pvt. Ltd.

Dec 2016 - Apr 2018

- Active participant in design and development of different app feature.
- Integerate latest android tools and standard library(Jetpack)
- Offline and different screen size product support.
- Work on App profiling, code maturity, and follow TDD(Test Driven Development) approach for developemnt.

ANDROID FRAMEWORK ENGINEER TPVision India Pvt. Ltd.

Jul 2012 - Jun 2016

- Android based TV development.
- Active participant in Mediaplayer customization.
- Exposure to DB stack, DRM, JNI, AIDL, Demux, Software decoder